AYUK, ROLAND OJONG

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A good Blockchain Developer/Full-Stack Developer with experience in development of web3/Blockchain applications. I have exceled in every stage in software development life cycle, including coding, debugging, testing and maintenance. Very good in devising innovative and tailored solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals in a variety of industries. Great skills and knowledge of leading programming tools with a strong background in mathematics, algorithms and data processing logic. While developing softwares, I focus more on Security, Performance and Media Responsiveness.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Excellent Project Management Skills
- Strong knowledge in Programming Language(JavaScript and Python)
- Strong Communication and Excellent Interpersonal Skill
- Fast pace learner
- Knowledge of Information Security Solutions
- Great Communication and Presentation Skills

SKILLS / FRAMEWORKS

BLOCKCHAIN: Solidity, Web3.js, Truffle, Ganache, Etherium

FRONTEND TECHNOLOGIES: React.js, Next.js, Redux, Typescript, Material UI, Styled-Components

BACKEND TECHNOLOGIES: Node.js(express.js), REST API, Heroku and Nginx Sever.

DATABASES: MongoDB, MySQL and PosgresQL.

SOURCE CONTROL & CI/CD: Git, Github and Github Actions

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Successfully been one of the core developers who built wowcatholic.com
- Won 5 times Developer of the Month at WOCA Group LTD
- Developed 3 personal projects, Expenses Tracker, video chat and kryptowatch

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

CRISET GROUP BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER

2022 – Present

Key Duties:

- Creating and deployment of Tokens into Etherium/BSC chains
- Developing Smart Contracts and deploying them.
- Integrating Web3.js into application frontend to get Blockchain data

WOCA GROUP LTD FULL-STACK DEVELOPER Key Duties:

2021 - 2022

- Improving existing features of the application and working on new features as the applications continue to scale
- Ensuring code quality and standards while meeting deadlines and delivering targets set by the product team.
- Working closely with product managers and data analysts to improve the overall software application, the design team to improve the user experience, and the front-end team for implementation

HP Technical LTD FRONT-END DEVELOPER

2019 -2021

Key Duties:

- Develop new User-interfaces features
- Refactoring and improving existing features of the product based on best practices, changing requirements and feedback from QA
- Writing Component Tests.
- Exchanging ideas with the design team to improve the user experience.
- Reviewing code to keep our code base clean, scalable and high performance.

PROJECTS

• Wowcatholic.com: <u>www.wowcatholic.com</u>

• Expense Tracker: www.roland-expense-tracker.netlify.app

• Video Chat Web App: <u>www.roland-video-app.netlify.app</u>

• Kryptowatch.org www.kryptowatch.org

TRAININGS/CERTIFICATIONS

2021

AWS CERTIFIED CLOUD PRACTIONER

• Ethical Hacking (EH) 2020

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

• B.Sc. Computer Science (Second Class Upper Division (Hons)) 2009-2013 West African Senior School Certificate Examination, 2004-2008.

BIO-DATA

Spoken Languages: English (Fluent)